## SAMUEL KAUFFMAN

407.754.5160 samuelkauffman@gmail.com sak55.github.io

**PROFILE** 

I'm dedicated to becoming a great front end developer—or getting as close to that goal as I can. After spending the last decade working in non-profits, it was time to pursue my lifelong passion of tech. I've spent the last few months pursuing this goal, first in my spare time, then through The Iron Yard's full-time Front End Engineering bootcamp in Orlando, Florida. Now I'm ready to take the next step and work full-time as a developer. I'm hoping you'll give me that opportunity.

**EDUCATION** 

2015 Front End Engineering
The Iron Yard

2001-2002 Master of Science, Sport Administration(Physical Education) — The Florida State University

2002 Global Sport Management Program Paris, France & London, England

1997-2001 Bachelor of Science, Sport Management (Education) — The Florida State University

**SKILLS** 

Web Development HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Angular, jQuery, Lodash, SASS,
Bootstrap, JASON APIs, Git, Gitflow, Github, Bower, Gulp, Yeoman,
Browser-Sync, Mocha, Chai, Responsive Design

**Software** Microsoft Office, Google Apps, Apple OS, iOS, iWork, iPhoto, iMovie, Adobe Photoshop

**EXPERIENCE** 

June 2014 - December 2014 Specialist at the Apple Store - Helped create the energy and Apple excitement around Apple products, providing the right solutions and getting products into customers' hands. Matched customer needs with the right products. Uncovered customers' needs, then followed through with enlightening solutions. As the first person customers meet when they enter the store, as well as the person who guided them — advised, sold, and even set up their new products. Other roles within the store included maintaining visual merchandising and assisting back of house team members.

October 2004 - July 2014 Central Florida Hillel Associate Director - Managed all aspects of program department; developed and administered program operational policies, procedures and systems. Through strategic vision & leadership supervised program personnel, establish annual program goals; initiated, planned, actualized and evaluated programs; maintained a relevant program. Researched and analyzed available information and data to plan strategies for engaging the student population not presently involved. Served as the liaison to campus organizations and relevant department and programs developed strong relationships with university officials and built coalitions where appropriate.

Interim Executive Director- Assumed duties of the executive director by representing organization in community, on campuses, and at national events, oversight of board governance, prepared and managed budget and fiscal policies, solicited and collected donations and awarded grants. Managed all aspects of programming and program staff on 4 campuses across central Florida. Implemented annual combined board retreat for 4 campus student boards and board of directors. Administered human resources policies, procedures, benefits, payroll, staff retreat, recruitment, retention, supervision, and staff development. Instituted a semi-annual staff day of service.

Assistant Executive Director - Board development responsibilities included preparation for meetings, recruitment, and cultivation. Managed fundraising event that led to highest net profit in organizational history. Administered human resources policies, procedures, benefits, and bi-weekly payroll. Prepared and managed budget that peaked at \$750k in conjunction with lay leadership and staff. Awarded grants, Oversaw programming operation on multiple campuses, hired, supervised, trained, evaluated, and developed professional staff, student staff, and interns. Managed facility and coordination of staff and vendors for maintenance and repairs. Coordinated development efforts, staffed immersive experiences, and identified strategies to decrease expenses and to refocus organization on mission during economic crisis.

Program Director - Developed and successfully implemented strategic student programming and outreach plans that increased market penetration by 300% and student leadership by 200%. Completed three straight years of successful programming under budget through an implemented action plan, assumed operational responsibilities and oversight in absence of an executive director, successfully awarded grants, produced unique curriculum and aspects of the first alternative spring break cruises to the - Bahamas including community service, history and learning, and collaboration with other foundations, successfully recruited, coordinated, and staffed hundreds of students attending immersive experiences.

Life Hacking, Hacking, Organizational Culture, Branding, UX, Innovation, Customer Service, Advertising, Sports, Outdoor Adventure, Traveling, and Cooking.

**INTERESTS**